# **Callum Donnelly**

Strategy Director: Senior digital / brand / creative strategist leveraging lean, agile principles to deliver rapid, growth focused strategy.

07794 937698 / callum@multiplyconsulting.co.uk

#### About me

My career to date has seen me lead high performing teams at the intersection of customer experience, marketing, brand and product. Most recently I was Managing Director of 40-strong Customer Experience Consultancy, Etch where I led the business from sub £1m to £4m turnover in 6 years.

Strategy has long been my passion, whether it be customer experience, digital or brand focused, I love figuring out the answer to a client's business problem and working with digital or creative teams to develop solutions that deliver growth as the key outcome. I previously held the role of Strategy Director at Five by Five and now through the launch of my own strategic consultancy, Multiply Consulting I am offering on demand strategy expertise to both agencies and brands looking to leverage digital, brand and creative strategy to achieve growth.

In my career to date, new business and account growth has been a key focus. I am very comfortable leading pitches from enquiry to win and growing existing client relationships through strategic advisory and partnership. I love digital, marketing and technology and make it my business to stay up to speed on industry developments and trends so I can take advantage of them in my work. I have learnt a lot through working in agencies but I believe the most important rule of all is not to let clients down - do that and the rest follows!

## **Key Skills**

Business strategy, digital strategy and roadmapping, brand strategy and development, product strategy, creative strategy, campaign development, channel planning, workshop facilitation, sales and marketing strategy.

## My highlights

- A 2 in 3 new business conversion rate.
- Lead the strategy and pitch to secure the Just Eat London creative account
- Lead the strategy and pitch to secure Watergate Bay Hotel account
- Lead the strategy on Quilter (previously Old Mutual Wealth), growing the account to £800k annual revenue
- Lead the strategy on Neptune Home growing them to £600k annual revenue
- Lead the strategy on The PIG Hotel group growing them to £800k annual revenue
- Developed the business strategy to take Etch from sub £1m to £4m turnover

## **Experience**

Managing Director / Digital Director - May 2016 - August 2022

Key Clients: Quilter, Neptune, Watergate Bay, The PIG Hotel Group Agencies: Etch

- Digital strategy for Quilter growing their annual agency revenue to £800k
- Go to market strategy for Neptune that saw their digital revenue exceed their digital + bricks and mortar revenue pre-pandemic

- Digital strategy for Watergate Bay that delivered efficiencies by driving bookings online
- Enterprise digital strategy for The PIG Hotel group that ensure their digital estate was fit for growth
- Brand development and go-to market strategy for challenger bank
- Brand development for Benefex

## Strategy Director - 2012 - 2016

Key Clients: Activision, Coopervision, Just Eat, GAP, Zyliss, New Look, The Body Shop, Pfaudler and IBMix Agencies: Five by Five

- Employee value proposition for The Body Shop
- Product strategy for GAP loyalty app
- Digital creative strategy for New Look
- Brand strategy and visual identity development for Pfaudler and IBMix
- Digital campaign strategy for Activision
- Digital creative strategy for Coopervision
- Digital creative strategy for Just Eat

# Head of Media / Media Planner/Buyer - 2005 - 2012

Key Clients: EA Games, THQ, National Trust, GAP, Vanquis, Red Funnel

Agencies: Five by Five

## For all key clients:

- Digital media strategy
- Channel planning
- Digital media planning + buying
- Campaign management
- Reporting + optimisation
- Paid search and social campaign set up and management

## **Key Education, Training and Achievements**

#### **Education:**

- 2002-2005 Solent University, Southampton, UK.
  2:1 BA (Hons) in Marketing, Media and Design (3yrs)
- 2000-2002 Brockenhurst College, Brockenhurst, UK.
  3 A D A Levels and 1 AS Level
- 1995 2000 The Mountbatten School, Romsey, UK.
  9 A C GCSEs

## Training:

- Scaling Up programme participant 2020 2022
- Various APG courses and conferences
- Sales training
- Presentation training

#### Awards:

• 2 x CXA award nominations for work with Quilter 2022

#### **Outside Interests**

- Golf (scratch handicap)
- Visiting new countries
- Trying new restaurants
- Watching the latest must-see box set
- Football Everton fan for my sins
- Dog walks I have a Miniature Dachshund

#### **Testimonials**

## Managing Director, Five by Five

"I had the pleasure of working with Callum for a number of years and during that time saw him transition from a skilled media planner into a credible and capable strategist.

He is a logical and strategic thinker who has the ability to not only distil a complex business issue but articulate the solution in such a way that it always makes perfect sense to any stakeholder.

A team player to his core Callum's calm and reassuring nature makes him a compelling presenter and he was always a very welcome addition to any pitch team or client meeting."

## Creative Director, Five by Five

"I worked closely with Callum for around four years on key accounts and new business pitches. For me, a strategist is at their best when they can take complexity and distil it into simple and powerful insight. This is something Callum has repeatedly demonstrated.

He's also very good at the tricky issue of challenging on work. We're a sensitive bunch and Callum's very good at winning people over while keeping the focus on the big picture. Clients love him because he has a quiet confidence that's reassuring. He's also a great listener, very rare in our business, a strong presenter and is ambitious in all the right ways.

All in all, I think Callum's a powerful, highly capable, marketer who brings big thinking and a collaborative approach. "

## Head of Client Experience, Etch

"Clients and new prospects are in very safe hands, with a background in media and digital marketing, Callum's knowledge is far reaching beyond this. Truly understanding the client, their needs and has unique ability to quickly see the vision and long term business transformation, often well beyond the first tactical or initial project.

Feedback from clients at Etch always overwhelmingly positive, seen as a pivotal and trusted contact. Always that partnership mentality at the forefront of his relationship building. He seamlessly walks the walk of any client in so many fields, sectors or industries."

**Notable Work** 

https://www.etchuk.com/products/case-study-quilter

https://www.etchuk.com/growth/case-study-the-pig

https://www.etchuk.com/growth/case-study-the-pig-custome-journey